
新约 -- 马太福音(Matthew) -- 第 1 章 ( 本篇共有 28 章 )    　


1:1    亚伯拉罕的后裔，大卫的子孙，耶稣基督的家谱。（后裔子孙原文都作儿子下同）
The book of the generation of Jesus Christ, the son of David, the son of Abraham.

1:2    亚伯拉罕生以撒。以撒生雅各。雅各生犹大和他的弟兄。
Abraham begat Isaac; and Isaac begat Jacob; and Jacob begat Judas and his brethren;

1:3    犹大从他玛氏生法勒斯和谢拉。法勒斯生希斯仑。希斯仑生亚兰。
And Judas begat Phares and Zara of Thamar; and Phares begat Esrom; and Esrom begat Aram;

1:4    亚兰生亚米拿达。亚米拿达生拿顺。拿顺生撒门。
And Aram begat Aminadab; and Aminadab begat Naasson; and Naasson begat Salmon;

1:5    撒门从喇合氏生波阿斯。波阿斯从路得氏生俄备得。俄备得生耶西。
And Salmon begat Booz of Rachab; and Booz begat Obed of Ruth; and Obed begat Jesse;

1:6    耶西生大卫王。大卫从乌利亚的妻子生所罗门。
And Jesse begat David the king; and David the king begat Solomon of her that had been the wife of Urias;

1:7    所罗门生罗波安。罗波安生亚比雅。亚比雅生亚撒。
And Solomon begat Roboam; and Roboam begat Abia; and Abia begat Asa;

1:8    亚撒生约沙法。约沙法生约兰。约兰生乌西亚。
And Asa begat Josaphat; and Josaphat begat Joram; and Joram begat Ozias;

1:9    乌西亚生约坦。约坦生亚哈斯。亚哈斯生希西家。
And Ozias begat Joatham; and Joatham begat Achaz; and Achaz begat Ezekias;

1:10    希西家生玛拿西。玛拿西生亚们。亚们生约西亚。
And Ezekias begat Manasses; and Manasses begat Amon; and Amon begat Josias;

1:11    百姓被迁到巴比伦的时候，约西亚生耶哥尼雅和他的弟兄。
And Josias begat Jechonias and his brethren, about the time they were carried away to Babylon:

1:12    迁到巴比伦之后，耶哥尼雅生撒拉铁。撒拉铁生所罗巴伯。
And after they were brought to Babylon, Jechonias begat Salathiel; and Salathiel begat Zorobabel;

1:13    所罗巴伯生亚比玉。亚比玉生以利亚敬。以利亚敬生亚所。
And Zorobabel begat Abiud; and Abiud begat Eliakim; and Eliakim begat Azor;

1:14    亚所生撒督。撒督生亚金。亚金生以律。
And Azor begat Sadoc; and Sadoc begat Achim; and Achim begat Eliud;

1:15    以律生以利亚撒。以利亚撒生马但。马但生雅各。
And Eliud begat Eleazar; and Eleazar begat Matthan; and Matthan begat Jacob;

1:16    雅各生约瑟，就是马利亚的丈夫。那称为基督的耶稣，是从马利亚生的。
And Jacob begat Joseph the husband of Mary, of whom was born Jesus, who is called Christ.

1:17    这样，从亚伯拉罕到大卫，共有十四代。从大卫到迁至巴比伦的时候，也有十四代。从迁至巴比伦的时候到基督，又有十四代。
So all the generations from Abraham to David are fourteen generations; and from David until the carrying away into Babylon are fourteen generations; and from the carrying away into Babylon unto Christ are fourteen generations.

1:18    耶稣基督降生的事，记在下面。他母亲马利亚已经许配了约瑟，还没有迎娶，马利亚就从圣灵怀了孕。
Now the birth of Jesus Christ was on this wise: When as his mother Mary was espoused to Joseph, before they came together, she was found with child of the Holy Ghost.

1:19    他丈夫约瑟是个义人，不愿意明明的羞辱他，想暗暗的把他休了。
Then Joseph her husband, being a just man, and not willing to make her a publick example, was minded to put her away privily.

1:20    正思念这事的时候，有主的使者向他梦中显现，说大卫的子孙约瑟，不要怕，只管娶过你的妻子马利亚来。因他所怀的孕，是从圣灵来的。
But while he thought on these things, behold, the angel of the LORD appeared unto him in a dream, saying, Joseph, thou son of David, fear not to take unto thee Mary thy wife: for that which is conceived in her is of the Holy Ghost.

1:21    他将要生一个儿子。你要给他起名叫耶稣。因他要将自己的百姓从罪恶里救出来。
And she shall bring forth a son, and thou shalt call his name JESUS: for he shall save his people from their sins.

1:22    这一切的事成就，是要应验主藉先知所说的话，
Now all this was done, that it might be fulfilled which was spoken of the Lord by the prophet, saying,

1:23    说，必有童女，怀孕生子，人要称他的名为以马内利。（以马内利翻出来，就是神与我们同在
Behold, a virgin shall be with child, and shall bring forth a son, and they shall call his name Emmanuel, which being interpreted is, God with us.

1:24    约瑟醒了，起来，就遵着主使者的吩咐，把妻子娶过来。
Then Joseph being raised from sleep did as the angel of the Lord had bidden him, and took unto him his wife:

1:25    只是没有和他同房，等他生了儿子，（有古卷作等他生了头胎的儿子）就给他起名叫耶稣。
And knew her not till she had brought forth her firstborn son: and he called his name JESUS.